<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi, I am Duc-Lam Doan on Duc-Lam Doan</title>
    <link>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hi, I am Duc-Lam Doan on Duc-Lam Doan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 11:13:32 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Word-embedding model for drugs and adverse drug reactions to support the work of negative-effect detections</title>
      <link>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/portfolio/project7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/portfolio/project7/</guid>
      <description>This is a project that I got involved at Uppsala Monitoring Centre (UMC - Link). UMC is a WHO-collaborating centre for drug safety and scientific research. Lucie G. has developed a word2vec (a natural language processing technique) model to build joint vector representations for drugs and adverse drug reactions (negative, side effects caused by drugs during treatment). Her work has been published (link) and used in signal (as known as potential side effects) detection at UMC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The impact of marketing campaigns on the total app trial traffic.</title>
      <link>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/portfolio/project6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/portfolio/project6/</guid>
      <description>Goal: A company has been running paid marketing on various platforms. The company wants to understand the true impact of the marketing campaigns on their total new trial traffic. This data project is aimed to:
 Analyse the data to see the number of new users and main contributing factors; Suggest for how to best allocate a marketing budget 50 000 USD over the next marketing period (28 days).  Data: The data from the last year includes two datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of variance - ANOVA</title>
      <link>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/posts/post7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/posts/post7/</guid>
      <description>This is a brief introduction about Analysis of variance as known as ANOVA. We will go through the concept of ANOVA, its assumptions, and how to perform a simple hypothesis testing using f-statistic in Python.
 What is ANOVA? ANOVA is to test for a difference overall between populations (groups). The test will help to answer the question that if there is at least one group is different from the others, however, we can not tell exactly, which group is the group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chi-square distribution and hypothesis testing using Chi-statistic</title>
      <link>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/posts/post6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/posts/post6/</guid>
      <description>This post is to describe Chi-square distribution and its applications in goodness-of-fit test and hypotheis testing.
1. What is Chi-square?  Assume that we observe an example of a categorical variable that has N different values, 1 through N. Each value has an expected (theoretical) frequency and an observed frequency. We can display them as the following table:      value 1 value 2 &amp;hellip; value N     Observed frequency O_1 O_2 &amp;hellip; O_N   expected frequency E_1 E_2 &amp;hellip; E_N     Chi-Square is the sum of the squared difference between the observed and expected frequency divided by the number of values of the variable: $$\chi^2 = \sum^{N}_{j=1} \frac{(O_j - E_j)^2}{E_j}$$  2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Network intrusion detector</title>
      <link>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/portfolio/project5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/portfolio/project5/</guid>
      <description>Task:  Build a predictive model capable of distinguishing between &amp;lsquo;bad&amp;rsquo; connections, called intrusions or attacks, and &amp;lsquo;good&amp;rsquo; normal connections. Differentiate between both the normal traffic and among distinct types of attack (predict the actual types (22 types) of attack).  Data:  The dataset was acquired, by Lincoln Labs, for nine weeks of raw TCP dump data for a local-area network (LAN) simulating a typical U.S. Air Force LAN. This Link is for more information about the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing two populations using hypothesis testing</title>
      <link>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/posts/post5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/posts/post5/</guid>
      <description>We will go through two examples where we use hypothesis testing to compare two populations; one example for sample proportions and the other for sample means.
Problem 1 (proportions)  A study shows the effect of a new drug on the treatment of a disease in two groups of patients: the first group received the drug and the other received placebo (no drug). The table below is the results:      n_patients n_cured proportion     new drug 250 150 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating customer behavior on Google Merchandise Store website using the Google Analytics dataset</title>
      <link>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/portfolio/project4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/portfolio/project4/</guid>
      <description>1. Goals: 1.1. Exploratory data analysis:  Number of views and number of unique users, Top ten products with the most views, Top top 10 selling products, Number of different eCommerceAction_type, Calculate revenue by month, How many % of the total visitors made a purchase, How many visitors bought on subsequent visits to the website?  1.2. Predictive analysis There were some customers who added products to carts but they removed the products from the carts or logged out without further processing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student&#39;s t-distribution and Confidence intervals using t-score</title>
      <link>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/posts/post3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/posts/post3/</guid>
      <description>This post is dedicated to describe T-distribution and how to use it for confidence intervals calculation, as well as hypothesis testing.
What is the T-distribution?   T-distribution is known as the Student distribution. T-distribution allows for use of small samples (n &amp;lt; 30) with an unknown standard deviation of population, however it does so by sacrificing certainty with a margin-of-error trade-off. It also has a bell-shaped distribution as normal distribution and it converges into a normal distribution when sample size n is high.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypothesis test using z-test (normal distribution)</title>
      <link>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/posts/post4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/posts/post4/</guid>
      <description>Problem 1 (proportions) Before an election, a candidate performed a poll to see how many percentages of voters plan on voting for him. The poll asked 500 people, the result shows that there is 54% of eligible voters gonna vote for him. He wants to do a hypothesis test to see if he&amp;rsquo;s gonna have an opportunity to win the election.
Approach Use one-tailed hypothesis test (Z test)
Step 1:   Define the hypotheses:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E-commerce price</title>
      <link>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/portfolio/project3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/portfolio/project3/</guid>
      <description>Goal: The blooming of e-commerce platforms over the last 2 decades makes the market become very competitive. To dominate the market they must provide customer with goods at lower prices. This project uses the data from an e-commerce platform to predict the goods price based on given features in the data.
Data: The data contains contains 2452 observations with 7 columns (features) and a target variable, Selling_price.
  Method: The exploratory data analysis (EDA) showed a highly skewed distribution of the selling price.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anomalies in ERP reports</title>
      <link>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/portfolio/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/portfolio/project2/</guid>
      <description>Overview and Objective: The data shows the business performance of an online shop in 2018. The shop manager has noticed anomalies in their ERP reports, and she is worried about the reliability of the data. The data consists of three dataset: CustomerData, ItemData, and TransactionData. The case-study goals are:
(1) We need to understand the data and develop a comprehensive understanding of the information provided.
(2) From this understanding we need to identify anomalies, consider important relationships, and report on any concern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon&#39;s tiny profits</title>
      <link>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/posts/post2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/posts/post2/</guid>
      <description>The visualisation shows the Amazon&amp;rsquo;s business model. The company is barely profitable. This is because it reinvests its profits rapidly into new innovative products. I made this for a #Makeover-Monday which is a weekly social data project. Click the link here for an interactive version of the plots.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loan status prediction</title>
      <link>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/portfolio/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/portfolio/project1/</guid>
      <description>Goal: A model can predict wether or not a borrower will pay back his/her loan. The model is trained with a given historical data that has information on whether or not the borrowers defaulted. The model can be used in the future to assess if a new customer is likely to pay back the loan.
Method: A deep neural network is used to address the problem. Since the data is imbalanced, it will be resampled (both under-sampled and over-sampled) to get better results of prediction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 40-year history of music industry</title>
      <link>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/posts/post1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/posts/post1/</guid>
      <description>This is a visualisation of the last 40-year history of music industry. I made this for a #Makeover-Monday which is a weekly social data project. The visualisation shows how the musics industry has changed in its revenue with different music format. The digital format prepares for an end of physical format. To interact with the plots, click here.
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
