<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Duc-Lam Doan</title>
    <link>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Duc-Lam Doan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chi-square distribution and hypothesis testing using Chi-statistic</title>
      <link>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/posts/post6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/posts/post6/</guid>
      <description>1. What is Chi-square?  Assume that we observe an example of a categorical variable that has N different values, 1 through N. Each value has an expected (theoretical) frequency and an observed frequency. We can display them as the following table:      value 1 value 2 &amp;hellip; value N     Observed frequency O_1 O_2 &amp;hellip; O_N   expected frequency E_1 E_2 &amp;hellip; E_N     Chi-Square is the sum of the squared difference between the observed and expected frequency divided by the number of values of the variable: $$\chi^2 = \sum^{N}_{j=1} \frac{(O_j - E_j)^2}{E_j}$$  2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing two populations using hypothesis testing</title>
      <link>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/posts/post5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/posts/post5/</guid>
      <description>Problem 1 (proportions)  A study shows the effect of a new drug on the treatment of a disease in two groups of patients: the first group received the drug and the other received placebo (no drug). The table below is the results:      n_patients n_cured proportion     new drug 250 150 0.60   placebo 245 118 0.48      We want to test if the new drug has a positive effect on the treatment or the result just happens by chance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student&#39;s t-distribution and Confidence intervals using t-score</title>
      <link>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/posts/post3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/posts/post3/</guid>
      <description>What is the T-distribution?   T-distribution is known as the Student distribution. T-distribution allows for use of small samples (n &amp;lt; 30) with an unknown standard deviation of population, however it does so by sacrificing certainty with a margin-of-error trade-off. It also has a bell-shaped distribution as normal distribution and it converges into a normal distribution when sample size n is high.
  Probability density function: $$ f(t) = \frac {\varGamma(\frac{v+1}{2})}{\sqrt{v\pi}\varGamma(\frac{v}{2})} (1+\frac{t^2}{v})^{-\frac{v+1}{2}}$$ Where $$\varGamma$$ is the gamma function, and v = n-1 is the number of degrees of freedom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypothesis test using z-test (normal distribution)</title>
      <link>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/posts/post4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/posts/post4/</guid>
      <description>Problem 1 (proportions) Before an election, a candidate performed a poll to see how many percentages of voters plan on voting for him. The poll asked 500 people, the result shows that there is 54% of eligible voters gonna vote for him. He wants to do a hypothesis test to see if he&amp;rsquo;s gonna have an opportunity to win the election.
Approach Use one-tailed hypothesis test (Z test)
Step 1:   Define the hypotheses:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon&#39;s tiny profits</title>
      <link>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/posts/post2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/posts/post2/</guid>
      <description>The visualisation shows the Amazon&amp;rsquo;s business model. The company is barely profitable. This is because it reinvests its profits rapidly into new innovative products. I made this for a #Makeover-Monday which is a weekly social data project. Click the link here for an interactive version of the plots.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 40-year history of music industry</title>
      <link>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/posts/post1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lamdoanduc.github.io/public/posts/post1/</guid>
      <description>This is a visualisation of the last 40-year history of music industry. I made this for a #Makeover-Monday which is a weekly social data project. The visualisation shows how the musics industry has changed in its revenue with different music format. The digital format prepares for an end of physical format. To interact with the plots, click here.
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
